Savannah Hammerton

PHD STUDENT, EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS

University of Georgia College of Public Health

🗆 423 544 2453 | 🔀 savannah.hammerton@uga.edu | 🌴 smhammerton.com | 🖸 smhammerton | 🛅 smhammerton

About

Graduate student working towards PhD in Epidemiology & Biostatistics (concentration in Data Analysis and Modeling). Particular interest and research emphasis in infectious diseases, infectious disease dynamics and modeling, and data analysis. Past experience in healthcare, providing strong contextual understanding of disease determinants, prevention, treatment, and outcomes, as well as an understanding of the real world implications of public health research and practice on individuals. This experience also drives context-aware data analytic approaches to answering epidemiological questions. Passionate and driven to build a career that benefits others.

Education

University of Georgia Athens, GA

PHD EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (DATA ANALYSIS & MODELING EMPHASIS)

University of Georgia Athens, GA

MS EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (EPIDEMIOLOGY EMPHASIS) | CERTIFICATE IN INFECTIOUS DISEASE EPIDEMIOLOGY

Columbus State University Columbus, GA

BS, Health Science

Chattanooga College Chattanooga, TN

DIPLOMA, PRACTICAL NURSING (SUMMA CUM LAUDE, DIRECTOR'S AWARD FOR CONSISTENT ACADEMIC AND CLINICAL

EXCELLENCE)

2014-2015

2022-Present

2020-2022

2018-2020

Relevant Experience _____

University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA 2022-Present

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISANT

- Assist Dr. Andreas Handel in research for the Center for Influenza Vaccine Research for High-Risk Populations (CIVR-HRP) grant at the University of Georgia. Aid in research and data analysis on influenza vaccines, particularly data related to universal influenza vaccine development.
- Perform secondary data analysis research on norovirus antibodies as correlates of protection to support vaccine research and development.
- · Use bayesian modeling approaches to answer complex research questions with human clinical trial data.

Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Center on Birth Defects and Developmental Disabilities

Atlanta, GA

RESEARCH EPIDEMIOLOGIST

2022-Present

- Support the MAT-LINK (MATernaL and Infant Network to Understand Outcomes Associated with Medication for Opioid Use Disorder during Pregnancy) team as SWEP (Student Worksite Experience Program) volunteer.
- Conduct data cleaning, analysis, and management using statistical software (e.g. SAS, R, etc.), and interpretation.
- Assist team with data quality assurance checks and other reviews of data. Conduct literature reviews related to opioid use disorder, pregnancy, and other topics.
- Develop instructional material on use of R and RMarkdown for reports and publications.
- Support the development of statistical briefs, standard operating procedures, and publically available code for outcome identification using ICD-9 and ICD-10 codes.
- · Perform primary and secondary analyses for manuscript development.

University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA

GRADUATE DEPARTMENTAL ASSISANT

- 2021-2022
- Assist in administrative departmental tasks, faculty retreats/meeting planning, and department event planning.
- Create and maintain spreadsheets on department classes, students, etc.
- Develop presentation materials and assist in orientation.
- Generate documents with information on degree programs, Graduate School processes, etc.
- Participate in research with Dr. Jose Cordero, planning and implementing a systematic review of environmental exposures and preterm birth.

Georgetown Behavioral Health Institute

Georgetown, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE 2016-2016

• LVN working on adolescent male and female units, military unit. Conducted medication administration, milieu management, conflict resolution, patient chart management. Responsible for verbal de-escalation of agitated patients, medical complication and event management. Aided in coordination of care between all health care providers.

Encompass Home Health Pediatrics

Temple, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE

2016-2016

Provided pediatric patient care for those needing 24-hour care or on hospice. Responsible for nutrition, hygiene, infection control, medication
administration, respiratory status maintenance. Provided support to families of patients and socialization to patients throughout shifts.

Research

Examining antibodies as correlates of protection against norovirus clinical outcomes

University of Georgia

MS THESIS PROJECT, ADVISOR - DR. ANDREAS HANDEL

2021-Present

Systematic review of norovirus challenge studies

University of Georgia

CO-AUTHOR

2022-Present

Certifications

Social and Behavioral Research

CITI Program 202.

Epidemics - The Dynamics of Infectious Diseases

COURSERA 2020

Certificate in Infectious Diseases and Disease Control

Allegra Learning Solutions 2020

Essentials of Public Health Research

CITI Program 2019

Research Involving Human Subjects

CITI Program 2019

Service

Athens Water Festival Athens, GA

VOLUNTEER September 2022

 Aided in setup and breakdown of annual Athens Water Festival. Collaborated with other volunteers to engage and educate children on marine life, Georgia biodiversity, and geology.

Graduate Scholars of Epidemiology & Biostatistics (GSEB)

University of Georgia

SECRETARY

2021-2022

Managed fundraising events and community food pantry. Planned and recorded regular executive board and general body meetings. Developed and led events open to department and college students. Maintained communication with department members to assess student needs and announce organization events. Maintained records for future executive board members.

College of Public Health Curriculum Committee

University of Georgia

STUDENT REPRESENTATIVE

2022-2023

Review, inform changes, and vote on new College of Public Health degrees, certificates, and classes.

Skills.

Data Analysis

PRIMARY CODING LANGUAGE: R | ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE IN: SAS, STATA, SPSS

Literature Searches and Management

ENDNOTE, ENDNOTE CLICK, ZOTERO

Laboratory Biosafety Level 2 Practices

EXPERIENCE IN SAFE MICROBIOLOGY LABORATORY PRACTICES WHEN WORKING WITH HUMAN PATHOGENS

Infectious Disease Modeling

UNDERSTANDING OF INFECTIOUS DISEASE MODELING CONCEPTS, AND EXPERIENCE IN FITTING INFECTIOUS DISEASE MODELS

Organization

SKILLED IN MANAGING MULTIPLE TASKS AND PROJECTS, MAINTAINING HIGH QUALITY OF WORK

Communication

EXPERIENCE IN CLINICAL, RESEARCH, AND PRIVATE GROUPS REQUIRING LARGE AMOUNTS OF COLLABORATION

Health Education

HAVE PROVIDED HEALTH EDUCATION IN BOTH CLINICAL AND NON-CLINICAL SETTINGS

Leadership/Management

EXPERIENCE IN MANAGEMENT, LEADERSHIP OF MULTIPLE EMPLOYEES

Presentations

Challenge Study Ethics

University of Georgia

INFECTIOUS DISEASE INTEREST GROUP

2022

• In collaboration with a colleague, developed and led a presentation on the background and basics of challenge studies (or, controlled human infection studies) and led a group discussion on ethical concerns and considerations in the studies themselves and whether data from unethical studies should be used as secondary analyses and publications.

Dengue Case-Control Study Review and Critique

University of Georgia

CASE-CONTROL DESIGN, IMPLEMETATION, AND ANALYSIS

2022

• Presented and critiqued "Risk factors of dengue fever in an urban area in Vietnam: a case-control study" by Nguyen-Tien et al. (2021) study design, methods, and analysis for epidemiology PhD case-control methods course.

Organizations ____

Graduate Scholars of Epidemiology & Biostatistics (GSEB)

Member

2021-Present

Center for the Ecology of Infectious Diseases (CEID)

Member

Eta Sigma Gamma (ESG) | Health Science Honor Society

2021-Present Member

American Public Health Association (APHA)

2019-2020 Member

2019-Present

Council of State and Territorial Epidemiologists (CSTE)

Member

2021-Present